Contact

tmbaker@texaschildrens.org

www.linkedin.com/in/toronda-baker-2588005a (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Nursing Education Critical Care Patient Safety

Certifications

BLS instructor

PALS

Certified Pediatric Nurse

Toronda Baker

Nursing Professional Development Specialist at Texas Children's Hospital

Spring, Texas

Summary

Experienced Nursing Specialist with a demonstrated history of working in the hospital & health care industry. Skilled in Nursing Education, Pediatric Advanced Life Support (PALS), Advanced Cardiac Life Support (ACLS), Critical Care Nursing, and Employee Training. Strong professional with a MSN focused in Nursing Education from Texas Tech University Health Sciences Center.

Experience

Texas Children's Hospital Nursing Professional Development Specialist July 2018 - Present (2 years)

Texas Children's Health Plan Education Development Specialist - The Center for Children and Women

April 2013 - July 2018 (5 years 4 months)

Houston, Texas Area

Texas Children's Hospital

7 years

RN- clinical nurse education coordinator January 2010 - April 2013 (3 years 4 months)

Texas children's hospital

Staff Nurse

May 2006 - January 2010 (3 years 9 months)

Critical care float pool, progressive care unit

Cross Country TravCorps

Travel nurse

December 2004 - May 2006 (1 year 6 months)

California, Georgia and arkansas

Johns Hopkins Hospital Nurse clinician II February 2001 - December 2004 (3 years 11 months)

Education

Texas Tech University Health Sciences Center MSN, Nursing Education · (2011 - 2013)

Grambling State University
BSN, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (1996 - 2000)